（干柿ほしがき鬼鮫きさめ）ん…
Now!
（マイト･ガイ）今だ！
水分身みずぶんしんの術
Water Clone Jutsu!
Water Prison Jutsu!
水牢すいろうの術
（日向ひゅうがネジ）ああっ
（テンテン）キャア！
Lee! Neji! Tenten!
（ガイ）リー！ ネジ！ テンテン！
（うずまきナルト）はあーっ！
螺旋丸らせんがん！
Rasengan!
This is a Shadow Clone too.
（ナルト）こいつも影分身(かげぶんしん)
うっ
あっ　サクラちゃん
Sakura-chan! Granny!
ばあちゃん
（チヨ）うう…
（春野はるのサクラ）うう…
Sakura...chan...?
サクラ… ちゃん？
あっ
（はたけカカシ）うっ ああ…
Kakashi-sensei!
（ナルト）カカシ先生
くっ
What's going on?!
どうなってるんだってばよ
This is awful...
（パックン）なんたることじゃ
These kids are better
than I thought...
（鬼鮫）思ったよりやり手で
びっくりしましたよ
I'm surprised.
このガキども
I can't move...
（ロック･リー）身動きが…
Damn it!
（ネジ）クソ！
（テンテン）ぐっ 息が…
I can't breathe...
（ガイ）うう…
（鬼鮫）
これで 邪魔者なしでやれますね
Now we can fight without
any interference.
I want to help them out...
（パックン）
なんとかしてやりたいが
But under these circumstances,
I'd just get in the way...
この状況では わしが出ていっても
足手まといになるばかりじゃの
Make it through, guys!
切り抜けてくれ
（物音）
（ガイ）ん？
This Great Shark Skin Sword
will only allow me  to use it.
（鬼鮫）この大刀だいとう･鮫肌さめはだは
私しか認めない
I see...
なるほど
不用意に 他人の武器を
使うものではないな
It's not a good idea to carelessly
use someone else's weapon.
（刺さる音）
（ガイ）うわっ
Then I'll use mine, too...
（ガイ）ならば 俺も
Those are... Nunchaku!
（テンテン）あれは ヌンチャク？
I can't believe
he's using Nunchaku...
（リー）ガイ先生が
ヌンチャクを使うなんて
（ネジ）それほどの
強敵だということか
This means the enemy's
just that powerful!
はあーっ！
はっ はっ…
えい！
I see...
なるほど
This is going to be interesting.
おもしろくなりそうですね
フフフ…
さあ 始めましょうか
Now, shall we begin?!
♪～
A voice heard in the distance gives me a hint.
tooku de kikoeru koe wo hinto ni
One by one like-minded people are standing up.
hitori mata hitori tachiagaru doushi
Lets overturn all the everyday, monotonous things.
kurikaesu dake no fudan doori kutsugaesu
I'm ready, are you ready?
junbi iize are you ready
A shiver spreads through my body, violently ringing stomping.
karadajuu furuwasu shindou ni hageshiku uchinarase yo stomping
Constantly stirring in me, it calls me.
taezu tsuki ugokasu call me
Catching that unchanging, never wavering story, Come on!
kawarazu yuru ga nutsukamu story come on
Everybody stand up! Today's the best time to get up!
everybody stand up agero kyou ichiban no jikan da
Before my eyes you still don't stop, speed hunter.
me ni mo tomaranu speed hunter
Everyone is a victim to that attraction, Yeah! (Come on!)
daremo ga mina toriko kanban yeah come on
Everybody Hands up! It's the highly anticipated Hero's Come Back!
everybody hands up matashita na hero's come back
Hold up your fingers and count down.
zujou kazoe yubi oru count down
Let's go, 3-2-1 make some noise!
ikuze 3-2-1 make some noise
Are you ready for a few risks?
hey yo whoa tashou no risuku wa kakugo desho
You have to get up no matter how many times you fall. (Get it on!)
nanka korundatte tatsu get it on
It's not some conspiracy, just a paper-thin session
nare ai ja nai ze kami hitoe no sesshon
The pent up feelings turn into a crystal.
irikunda kanjou kidzukiageta kesshou
The rising cheers will become your courage.
wakiagaru kansei ga yuuki tonaru
So stand up now, no matter how much pain you feel.
tachiagareba ima ijou kurushimi tomonau
But in the end I'm sure you'll laugh.
soredemo saigo wa kitto warau
Everything will be swept away in victory and cheer.
subete sarau shouri to kansei
Everybody stand up! Today's the best time to get up!
everybody stand up agero kyou ichiban no jikan da
Before my eyes you still don't stop, speed hunter.
me ni mo tomaranu speed hunter
Everyone is a victim to that attraction, Yeah! (Come on!)
daremo ga mina toriko kanban yeah come on
Everybody Hands up! It's the highly anticipated Hero's Come Back!
everybody hands up matashita na hero's come back
～♪
Hold up your fingers and count down.
zujou kazoe yubi oru count down
Let's go, 3-2-1 make some noise!
ikuze 3-2-1 make some noise
Naruto's
Growth
（ナルト）うっ
う…
（ナルト）影分身なのか
Are they Shadow Clones?
あっ
And I didn't even look
at his eyes...!
目は見なかったのに
クソッ なんで幻術げんじゅつに
Damn it... How'd I get caught
in his Genjutsu...?
These eyes aren't the only way
I can activate a Genjutsu.
（うちはイタチ）この目だけが
幻術を発動する手段ではない
I can do it with one finger.
この指１本あれば それは可能
はっ
（イタチ）そろそろ
一緒に来てもらうことにするよ
It's about time for you to
come with me...
Naruto-kun.
ナルト君
It must've been back then...
（ナルト）あのときか
Rest easy.
（イタチ）安心しろ
I won't use the
Mangekyo Sharingan.
万華鏡写輪眼まんげきょうしゃりんがんは使わない
Or I guess I should say
I can't  use it right now...
というより
今は使えないと言ったほうが
正しいか
（ナルト）う…
What do you mean by that?
それってば どういうことだ
You don't need to know.
（イタチ）君が知る必要はない
それより そろそろ眠ってもらおう
More importantly, it's about time
you went to sleep.
（ナルト）くっ
Damn it...
And I was so careful...
（ナルト）クソッ
あんだけ気をつけていたのに
幻術をくらうなんて
I can't believe I got caught
in a Genjutsu...!
Genjutsu?
（ナルト）幻術？
Are you going to teach me Genjutsu,
Pervy Sage?!
幻術 教えてくれんのか？
エロ仙人
（自来也じらいや）正しくは
幻術を解く方法をだ
To be exact, I'm going to teach you
how to break a Genjutsu.
How to break... a Genjutsu...?
（ナルト）うん 幻術を解く方法？
いいかのォ ナルト
Listen up, Naruto.
There's a trick to breaking
a Genjutsu if you get caught in one--.
幻術をくらったときは
解くのにコツがある
Pervy Sage.
（ナルト）エロ仙人
そのコツというのは
お前もよく知っている…
You should know that trick very well...
（ナルト）エロ仙人てばよ
Hey, Pervy Sage!
なんじゃ
What?!
幻術くらったときのことより
I want to know about
how to cast a Genjutsu,
not about if I get caught in one!
幻術のかけ方を教えてくれよ
Huh?
はい？
（自来也）ハァ…
Wh-What's up with that reaction?!
なんだよ そのリアクションは
Listen up, Naruto...
（自来也）いいか ナルト
A Genjutsu works on
an opponent's five senses.
幻術というのは
相手の五感に働きかけ
You can control the Chakra flowing
through their cerebral nervous system.
その脳神経系に流れるチャクラを
己がコントロールするという
It's a Ninjutsu requiring
a great deal of intelligence.
かなり高度なインテリ忍術だ
うーん… よく分かんねえ
Hmm... I don't really get it...
I didn't think so...
（自来也）だろうな
Nobody is telling you to
master Genjutsu.
だから 誰もお前に
幻術を使いこなせとは言っとらん
そもそも お前は まるっきり
幻術タイプの忍ではないからのォ
You're not a Genjutsu-type Shinobi
at all in the first place...
Huh? Really?
（ナルト）えっ？ そうなの？
（自来也）うん
（ナルト）なっ…
Then forget about Genjutsu!
じゃあ もう幻術はいいってばよ
次の修業をしよう 次の修業
Let's get to my next training,
my next training!
That won't do!
（自来也）そうもいかんのだ
Why not?!
なんでだよ
Some enemies use Genjutsu,
after all.
敵には 幻術使いがいるんだからのォ
For example, Uchiha Itachi!
例えば うちはイタチ
な…
う～ん…
Come to think of it,
そういや ヤツの術で
カカシ先生も倒されてたってばよ
even Kakashi-sensei
was beaten by his technique...
That's why you need to know
how to deal with Genjutsu!
だから 幻術への対処法は
ちゃんとやっておく
（ナルト）う…
Fine.
分かったってばよ
When you're in a Genjutsu,
（自来也）幻術中は
the Chakra inside your head
is being controlled.
相手に 頭の中のチャクラを
コントロールされとる状態だ
So if you get caught in one,
だから もし幻術をくらったら
make sure you temporarily stop
いったん 己のチャクラの流れを
可能なかぎり止めるよう...
the flow of your own Chakra
as best you can.
心がけろ
Stop the flow... of Chakra...?
チャクラの流れを止める？
Thanks to your training until now,
お前も これまでの修業のおかげで
you've subconsciously
concentrated Chakra
今では無意識のうちに
チャクラを足の裏に集中させて
at the bottom of your feet and
are standing on the water.
水の上に立っとる
（ナルト）あ… そういえば
Now that you mention it...
You need to temporarily stop all of it.
Give it a try.
（自来也）これらも
全ていったんストップさせろ
やってみい！
Right!
おう！
まずは チャクラの流れを
止めりゃあいいんだな
First, I need to stop
the flow of Chakra.
ああっ
ハアッ
Then with power greater
than your opponent,
（自来也）そこで すかさず
一気に相手を上回る力で
you need to immediately disrupt
the flow of Chakra in one shot!
チャクラの流れを乱す
Got it!
分かったってばよ
はあーっ！
If you do that...
（自来也）そうすれば 幻術は解ける
the Genjutsu will be broken!
（イタチ）ん？
（ナルト）はあーっ！
（ガイ）おりゃ！
うう…
おりゃ！
（鬼鮫）フフフ…
（リー）ガイ先生
Guy-sensei...!
（ネジ）ぐっ う…
（テンテン）ぐ… そろそろ息が…
I'm running out of breath...
（ガイ）テンテンは もう限界か
Tenten's reached her limit, huh...?
（鬼鮫）水遁すいとん･水鮫弾すいこうだんの術
Water Style: Shark Bomb Jutsu!
そりゃ！
ぬあーっ！
（ガイ）くっ なんて怪力だ
What incredible power...
そうか お前は
I know! You're...
今ごろ思い出しても遅いですよ
It's too late for you...
to remember now!
ぬあーっ！
グハッ
（リー）ガイ先生
Guy-sensei!
（テンテン）ガイ先生 まさか…
Guy-sensei... Don't tell me...!
（リー）あの程度でやられる
ガイ先生じゃありません
Guy-sensei won't
be beaten that easily!
（ガイ）う… うう…
あの男 確かにどこかで
That guy...
I know I've met him somewhere...
（鬼鮫）ふん
この程度で借りを返し終えたと
思わないでください
Don't think I'm done settling
the score just yet.
水遁･五食鮫ごしょくざめ！
Water Style...
Five Hungry Sharks!
（ガイ）あ…
（鬼鮫）一食
First Meal!
二食
Second Meal!
三食
Third Meal!
（ガイ）効かんか…
No effect, huh...?
（鬼鮫）四食
Fourth Meal!
五食
Fifth Meal!
ふん
五食の鮫たちが
My five sharks will completely devour you
and leave no bones!
骨も残さず
食いつくして差し上げますよ
（リー）テンテン
Tenten!
（ネジ）まずいな 限界だ
This is not good...
She's reached her limit...
（ガイ）これ以上
手間取るわけにはいかんか
I can't be slowed down any further...
しかたない
I have no choice...
ん？ なんのおつもりです？
What's he planning?
（ガイ）八門遁甲(はちもんとんこう) 第一 開門(かいもん) 開(かい)
The Eight Inner Gates...
First Gate, Gate of Opening, Open!
（ガイ）第二 休門(きゅうもん)
Second Gate, Gate of Rest.
（鬼鮫）ん？
（ガイ）第三 生門(せいもん)
Third Gate, Gate of Life.
（ガイ）第四 傷門(しょうもん)
Fourth Gate, Gate of Pain.
なんです？
この異常な体力回復力は
What's this remarkable power...?
（ガイ）第五 杜門(ともん) 開
Fifth Gate, Gate of Closing, Open!
（鬼鮫）なん…
What?!
（リー）こ… これは
Wh-What's that?!
（ネジ）
水中から すさまじい量の
チャクラが放出されている
There's an incredible amount of Chakra
being emitted from the water!
（パックン）ガイのヤツ
まさか あれを使う気なのか
Guy...
Surely he's not going to
use that, is he?
やあーっ！
八門遁甲 第六 景門けいもん 開！
The Eight Inner Gates! Sixth Gate,
Gate of Joy... Open!
これは
What's this?!
（ガイ）うおー！
こん…
（ネジ）今だ
Now!
ここ
Here!
（ネジ）八卦六十四掌はっけろくじゅうよんしょう
8 Trigrams 64 Palms!
はあっ！
（リー）木こノ葉は大旋風だいせんぷう！
Severe Leaf Hurricane!
（ネジ）大丈夫か テンテン
Are you okay, Tenten?
（テンテン）ハッ
うん
Y-Yeah... Thanks, Neji...
ありがとう ネジ
（リー）助かりました
We're saved...
あっ
あの構えは
That stance is...!
（ナルト）はあーっ！
（イタチ）成長している
He has grown.
（ナルト）やあーっ！
When I look up at the sky.
sora wo miagereba
♪～
The stars, see, are sparkling.
hoshitachi ga hora matataiteru
Each giving off its own light.
kono hoshi no hitotachi mitai ni
Like the people on this planet.
samazama na hikari wo hanatte
Yeah, so among them, I too,
sono naka de boku mo
want to shine particularly bright.
hitokiwa kagayaite itain da
I close my eyes and make a vow in my heart,
me wo tojite kokoro ni chikau
and entrust my dreams to that shooting star.
nagareboshi ni yume wo takushite
I'm in my usual park.
koko wa itsumo no kouen
I can see the night scenery on the slide.
yakei ga mieru suberidai no ue
That's been my special seat for years.
mukashi kara boku no tokutouseki
Whenever I'm worried about something, I come here.
nayami ga areba koko ni kurun desu
Just like then, I'm on my way to my dreams.
ano koro no mama yume no tochuu de
But unable to fulfil them.
ima de kanaerarezu ni irun desu
Maybe this is the end of the line.
moshikashite koko ga mou shuuten
There are days when I say weak things like that.
nante yowane wo haite shimaisou na hi mo aru
But every time, I remember.
demo sono tabi ni omoidasu
That starry sky where I looked for a shooting star.
nagareboshi wo sagashite ano hoshizora
The wish I made when I was little hasn't changed even now.
chiisana koro no negaigoto ima mukashi mo kawaranai mama
When I look up at the sky.
sora wo miagereba
The stars, see, are sparkling.
hoshitachi ga hora matataiteru
Each giving off its own light.
kono hoshi no hitotachi mitai ni
Like the people on this planet.
samazama na hikari wo hanatte
Yeah, so among them, I too,
sono naka de boku mo
want to shine particularly bright.
hitokiwa kagayaite itain da
I close my eyes and make a vow in my heart,
me wo tojite kokoro ni chikau
～♪
and entrust my dreams to that shooting star.
nagareboshi ni yume wo takushite
Next Episode
Next, Uzumaki Naruto-san.
Come on back.
次 うずまきナルトさん
どうぞ
Doctor, something's wrong
with my body!
先生 大変だ 俺の体
Doctor, what's this?
先生 これは…
Hmm, it's some terribly dry skin.
うーん すごい肌荒れだね
No, it's not just that!
いや そこだけじゃなくて
また これは大きな魚の目
Oho, this is sure a large corn.
Look at this, too!
こっちも見てくれってばよ
Th-That large growth on your shoulder...!
そ… その肩の大きなできものは
Hmm, it's the boil
I've heard rumors about, no mistake.
間違いなくウワサに聞く人面瘡じんめんそうだ
Doctor, what should I do?
先生 どうすれば
Oh, you don't need to worry.
The baby in your belly is doing just fine!
ご心配なく
おなかの赤ちゃんは
順調ですからね
- What?!
- Congratulations.
おめでとうございます
Hey, just a minute. I'm a guy!
ちょっと待った
俺は男だぞ
Next episode: The Secret Weapon is Called...
The Secret Weapon is Called...!
次回「隠し玉
名付けて…！」
Guide to the Clans of
the Leaf Village, Volume 1
（ネジ）木ノ葉一族図鑑 第壱巻
In the Leaf there are shinobi clans
with inherited special powers.
木ノ葉には 特殊な能力を受け継ぐ
忍の一族が存在する
And so today we will be doing
a feature on the Hyuga Clan!
（テンテン）そこで 今回は
日向一族を特集しちゃいます
（ネジ）テンテン
よけいなことは話すなよ
Tenten, make sure you
watch what you say.
You can't talk about the Hyuga family
without mentioning the Byakugan!
（テンテン）
日向家といえば白眼(びゃくがん)よね
Using the Byakugan, we can
see the flow of the Chakra Network
（ネジ）白眼によって俺たちは
相手の体内を流れる
チャクラの経絡系けいらくけいや
in an opponent's body
as well as their Chakra Points.
チャクラ穴けつを
見極めることができる
In other words, you can
see lots of stuff, right?
（テンテン）要は
いろいろ見えるってことでしょ
You could say that.
（ネジ）ざっくり切ったな
白眼を使った奥義が
This is the 8 Trigrams 64 Palms
secret technique,
八卦六十四掌だ
8 TRIGRAMS 64 PALMS
which utilizes the Byakugan.
With this technique, we can
stop the chakra flow of an opponent
八卦の
領域にいる...
敵の六十四の点穴てんけつを
突くことで
相手のチャクラの
流れを止める術だ
within range of the 8 Trigrams
by hitting all 64 of their Chakra Points.
（テンテン）
ところでさ
質問なんだけど
By the way, I've got a question.
（ネジ）なんだ
What is it?
What was Hinata's little sister's
name again?
（テンテン）ヒナタの妹って
なんて名前だっけ
The name of Hinata-sama's little sister?
That would be...
（ネジ）ヒナタ様の妹の名？
それは…
"Question: What is the name of Hinata's little sister?"
（ネジ）
日向ハナビ様だ
"Answer: Hyuga Hanabi"
Answer: Hyuga Hanabi-sama.
There was an odd pause there.
今 変な間があったよね
It... it's just your imagination!
気… 気のせいだ
（テンテン）アハハ…